A Guide to the James Branch Cabell Collection
University of Virginia Library
- Scrapbook 5, 1920-1921
  - Edward J. O'Brien to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Sep 30; TLS, 1 p.
  - Louise Leonard to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Oct 27; TLS, 1 p.
  - Frank Crowninshield to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Aug 31; TLS, 1 p.
  - John Peale Bishop to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Sep 1; TLS, 1 p.
  - Franz Blei to [Maurice J.] Speiser, 1921 Sep 15; TLS, 1 p.
  - Dorothy Scarborough to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Nov 27; TLS, 3 p.
  - Blanche Colton Williams to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Nov 21; TLS, 1 p.
  - Frances Fenmore to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Oct 18; TLS, 1 p.
  - Frederick S. Hammett to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Dec 11; TLS, 2 p.
  - Edward Hale Bierstadt to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Nov 30; TLS, 2 p.
  - Mitchell S. Buck to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Dec 14; ALS, 1 p.
  - Ben Ray Redman to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Dec 6; TLS, 2 p.
  - Christopher [Hageruss] to James Branch Cabell, [1921] Nov 26; ALS, 2 p.
  - Thomas Lloyd Lennon to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Nov 29; TLS, 1 p.
  - LeRoy Arnold to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Dec 23; ALS, 3 p.
  - Harold Chapman Brown to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Jan 19; TLS, 1 p.
  - Charles Romm to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Dec 20; TLS, 1 p.
  - R. de Roussy de Sales to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Nov 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - Franz Blei to [Maurice J.] Speiser, 1921 Dec 1; TLS, 2 p.
  - Franz Blei to Speiser, 1921 Dec 26; TLS, 1 p.
  - Irving L. Dilliard to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Feb 14; ALS, 1 p.
  - Eva Scofield to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Feb 8; ALS, 2 p.
  - Marshall Wingfield to James Branch Cabell, [1921]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Lucille Levy to [ James Branch Cabell], n.d.; ALS, 3 p.
  - Harold Chapman Brown to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Feb 9; TLS, 2 p.
  - Martha McCoy to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Mar 31; ALS, 3 p.
  - Martha McCoy to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Apr 21; ALS, 2 p.
  - Thomas R. Palfrey to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Apr 27; TLS, 1 p.
  - W[illiam] Leete Stone to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Apr 23; TLS, 1 p.
  - J.A. De Lacey to James Branch Cabell, w/auto. postscript, 1922 Apr 24; TLS, 1 p.
  - Edward Hale Bierstadt to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Dec 3; TLS, 1 p.
  - William J. Bernhard to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Apr 11; ALS, 3 p.
  - Laurence Schwab to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Mar 6; TLS, 1 p.
  - [ Frederick Fender] to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Mar 24; ALS, 1 p.
  - Cary Franklin Jacob to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Jan 19; TLS, 1 p.
  - John Peale Bishop to James Branch Cabell, [1922]; ALS, 1 p.
  - Wilson O. Clough to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Mar 31; TLS, 1 p.
  - Abraham Cahan to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Mar 28; TLS, 1 p.
  - Carl Van Doren to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Mar 27; TLS, 1 p.
  - Gustav Gruener to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Apr 24; ALS, 2 p.
  - Henry Seidel Canby to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Mar 2; TLS, 1 p.
  - Sam Janney to [ James Branch Cabell], 1921 Dec 1; TLS, 1 p.
  - F. Scott Fitzgerald to James Branch Cabell, [1922]; Telegram
  - Basil Thompson to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Mar 22; ALS, 1 p.
  - Merle Johnson to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Jan 10; ALS, 2 p.
  - Alexander Singleton to James Branch Cabell, [1922]; ALS, 1 p.
  - Carl Van Doren to James Branch Cabell, 1921 Dec 7; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ben Ray Redman to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Mar 19; ALS, 1 p.
  - Maud Skidmore Barber to James Branch Cabell, 1922 May 16; TLS, 2 p.
  - Charles Ridgely to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Apr 17; ALS, 2 p.
  - Lillian Young Cox to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Jan 16; ALS, 2 p.
  - Thomas Caldecot Chubb to James Branch Cabell, 1922 May 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - John M. Price to James Branch Cabell, 1922 May 24; ALS, 1 p.
  - Ruth Wyatt Tongue to James Branch Cabell, 1922 May 21; TLS, 1 p.
  - F. L. Schneider to Robert McBride and Co., 1922 Jun 28; TLS, 1 p.
  - [ Charles Keiller] to James Branch Cabell, 1922 May 25; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ralph Parker Anderson to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Jun 25; TLS, 1 p.
  - Hal Garrott to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Jul 4; TLS, 2 p.
  - M. B. Gottlieb to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Jun 9; TLS, 1 p.
  - Glen Walton Blodgett to James Branch Cabell, 1922 May 31; TLS, 1 p.
  - G. W. Freeman to James Branch Cabell, 1922 Sep 1; TLS, 1 p.
  Scrapbook 6
- Scrapbook 6, 1923-1924
  The Cream to the Jest
  The High Place
  , with some letters, listed below, 100 p.
  - J. Coupet-Sarraille to James Branch Cabell, 1923 May 22; ALS, 2 p.
  - Harry Hervey to James Branch Cabell, [1923]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Boudinot Colt to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Jul 20; ALS, 2 p.
  - H. W. Stewart to James Branch Cabell, 1923 May 29; TL, 1 p.
  - J. J. Taylor to James Branch Cabell, [1923] Oct 15; TLS, 1 p.
  - Eleanor V. Cederstrom to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Oct 3; TLS, 1 p.
  - S. D. Green to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Oct 23; TLS, 1 p.
  - Edith M. Parkinson to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Oct; ALS, 8 p.
  - C. Ford to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Jan 14; ALS, 3 p.
  - Jessie Burns to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Jul 17; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ralph Block to Charlton Andrews, 1923 Sep 22; TLS, 1 p.
  - Secretary of George Brandes to Maurice J. Speiser, 1923 Oct 23; ALS, 1 p.
  - Maurice J. Speiser to George Brandes(carbon), 1923 Sep 14; TL, 1 p.
  - Maurice J. Speiser to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Nov 9; TLS, 1 p.
  - Don Bregenzer to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Jul 10; TLS, 1 p.
  - Frederick Eddy to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Oct 6; TLS, 1 p.
  - Thomas Caldecot Chubb to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Oct 6; TLS, 1 p.
  - Charles Parsons to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Oct 14; TLS, 2 p.
  - Don Bregenzer to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Nov 15; TLS, 1 p.
  - Poem, "The Hidden Way" by Carr Liggett, 1922 Oct 22; TMs, 1 p.
  - Frank H[orace] Vizetelly to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Oct 31; TLS, 1 p.
  - Alfred T. Goldsmith to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Nov 13; Telegram
  - Florence Blackstone to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Nov 13; ALS, 1 p.
  - R. E. MacKenzie to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Nov 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - Carl Van Vechten to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Nov 23; ALS, 1 p.
  - Ben Ray Redman to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Nov 26; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Beveridge to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Nov 15; ALS, 4 p.
  - Edwin [Björkman] to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Dec 14; ALS, 2 p.
  - Donald Barr Chidsey to James Branch Cabell, [1923]; TLS, 2 p.
  - H. Randolph [Carr] to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Nov 26; ALS, 2 p.
  - Lucy Curtis Templeton to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Dec 7; ALS, 2 p.
  - Evelyn Campbell to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Dec 7; ALS, 4 p.
  - Unknown to James Branch Cabell, [1923]; AL, 3 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Dec 16; ALS, 4 p.
  - Garrard Glenn to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Dec 17; TLS, 1 p.
  - Stanley E. Babb to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Dec 17; TLS, 1 p.
  - Howard Stanley Aronson to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Dec 18; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Harvey Robinson to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Dec 13; TLS, 1 p.
  - Dhan Gopal Mukerji to James Branch Cabell, [1923] Dec 7; ALS, 4 p.
  - Henry S[eidel] Canby to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Dec 20; TLS, 1 p.
  - K. W. Lane to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Mar 11; TLS, 1 p.
  - Virginia MacFadyen to James Branch Cabell, [1923]; ALS, 1 p.
  - H. L. Mencken to James Branch Cabell, [1924] Jan 2; TLS, 1 p.
  - Arthur Hartmann to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Dec 14; TLS, 1 p.
  - Carleton Beals to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Jan 3; TLS, 1 p.
  - Charles A. Berst to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Jan 6; TLS, 1 p.
  - Charles E. Noyes to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Jan 1; TLS, 3 p.
  - Walter B. [Wolfe] to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Jan 2; TLS, 1 p.
  - Deborah Hathaway [Calkins] to Robert McBride and Co., encl. 10 pp. assignment sheet for course in the novel, re: James Branch Cabell, 1924 Jan 4; TLS, 1 p.
  - Calvin Neff to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Jan 20; ALS, 3 p.
  - Charles F. [Pierce] to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Dec 31; ALS, 2 p.
  - George Steele Seymour to James Branch Cabell, 1923 Dec 26; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ben Ray Redman to James Branch Cabell, w/auto. postscript, 1924 Jan 18; TLS, 1 p.
  - Phoebe H. Gilkyson to James Branch Cabell, [1924]; ALS, 4 p.
  - W. Cabell Greet to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Jan 19; TLS, 1 p.
  - Dorothy G. Hyde to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Jan; TLS, 2 p.
  - George T. Keating to James Branch Cabell, encl. 2 pp. ALS, [1924], Joseph Fisher Loewi to Keating, 1924 Jan 22; TLS, 1 p.
  - C[larence] J. Laughlin to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Jan 20; TLS, 2 p.
  - Lewis Galantiére to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Feb 2; TLS, 2 p.
  - Mildred H. Lewis to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Feb 5; TLS, 3 p.
  - Maurice De Koven to James Branch Cabell, encl. 4 pp. TMs "Of Compromises in Ogygia" by De Koven, 1924 Feb 18; TLS, 1 p.
  - Edith M. Parkinson to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Feb 11; ALS, 2 p.
  - C. Ford to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Feb 15; ALS, 3 p.
  - Howard Stanley Aronson to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Feb 26; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ward Edwards to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Feb 25; ALS, 4 p.
  - Henry S[eidel] Canby to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Jan 22; TLS, 1 p.
  - Loyd Ring Coleman to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Mar 8; TLS, 1 p.
  - Aug[ustus] Cabell to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Mar 4; TLS, 1 p.
  - Clarence J. Laughlin to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Mar 22; TLS, 4 p.
  - Horace H. Edwards to Ballard Cabell, w/envelope, 1958 Feb 18; TLS, 1 p.
  - Don Bregenzer to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Apr 11; Telegram
  - I. R. Brussel to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Jun 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - Alfred W. Lublin to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Apr 17; ALS, 1 p.
  - Helene Gent to James Branch Cabell, 1924 May 11; ALS, 2 p.
  - Charles C. Baldwin to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Apr 21; TLS, 1 p.
  - Don Bregenzer to James Branch Cabell, 1924 May 3; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ben Ray Redman to James Branch Cabell, 1924 May 8; TLS, 1 p.
  - Donald Barr Chidsey to James Branch Cabell, n.d.; TLS, 3 p.
  - Mary Webster to James Branch Cabell, [1924] Apr 18; TLS, 1 p.
  - Homer Hendricks to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Apr 29; TLS, 2 p.
  - Arthur W. Johnson to James Branch Cabell, [1924]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Raoul Rodriguez to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Apr 15; TLS, 3 p.
  Scrapbook 7
- Scrapbook 7, 1924-1925
  Clippings re: Straws and Prayer-Books, and
  , with letters as follows, 102 p.
  - C[harles] B[attel] Loomis, Jr. to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Jun 14; ALS, 4 p.
  - Charles Battel Loomis, Jr. to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Jun 13; TLS, 3 p.
  - Milton I. D. Einstein to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Jun 24; TLS, 1 p.
  - Arthur W. Johnson to James Branch Cabell, 1924; TLS, 1 p.
  - Bruce Lockwood to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Sep 15; TLS, 1 p.
  - Maurice K. Weil to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Jul 7; TLS, 2 p.
  - Miriam Thurman to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Nov 2; ALS, 3 p.
  - A. Mary Barclay to James Branch Cabell, [1924]; TLS, 3 p.
  - George Williams to James Branch Cabell, [1924] Nov 15; ALS, 1 p.
  - Geoffrey Landsman to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Jul 9; ALS, 4 p.
  - Louise Lafitte to James Branch Cabell, [1924]; TL, 2 p.
  - Charles Alexander to James Branch Cabell, [1924] Nov 10; TLS, 2 p.
  - David Werner Amram to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Nov 7; ALS, 2 p.
  - Zora Putnam Wilkins to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Oct 28; ALS, 3 p.
  - Howard Stanley Aronson to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Nov 8; ALS, 1 p.
  - Warren A. McNeill to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Nov 20; TLS, 1 p.
  - Howard Stanley Aronson to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Dec 2; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Oct 17; TLS, 1 p.
  - Laurence Stallings to James Branch Cabell, [1924]; ALS, 1 p.
  - Frances Newman to James Branch Cabell, [1924] Oct 28; TLS, 1 p.
  - Frances Newman to James Branch Cabell, [1924] Nov 11; TLS, 1 p.
  - George C. Calvert to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Nov 20; TLS, 1 p.
  - Carl Van Vechten to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Oct 19; ALS, 2 p.
  - Edwin Björkman to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Oct 19; TLS, 2 p.
  - Dhan Gopal Mukerji to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Nov 21; TLS, 1 p.
  - R. Critchell Rimington to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Nov 24; TLS, 1 p.
  - Carl D. Herdman to James Branch Cabell, encl. 1 p. TL (carbon), 1922 February 14, Herdman to Cooper Wilkins, and 4 pp. TL (carbon), 1922 February 15, Herdman to Wilkins, 1924 Nov 26; TLS, 2 p.
  - Frederick S. Hammett to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Nov 30; TLS, 1 p.
  - A. L. S. Wood to James Branch Cabell, [1924]; TNS, 1 p.
  - Leonard Cline to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Dec 8; TLS, 1 p.
  - Laban Lacy Rice to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Dec 5; ALS, 2 p.
  - G. C. Hite, Jr. to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Dec 4; TLS, 1 p.
  - Christine Hamilton to James Branch Cabell, [1924] Dec 7; ALS, 2 p.
  - George Sylvester Viereck to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Dec 18; TLS, 1 p.
  - Maude V. P. Hazelton to James Branch Cabell, [1924]; ALS, 6 p.
  - Frances L. Phillips to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Dec 26; ALS, 1 p.
  - Brace M. Conning to James Branch Cabell, [1924]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Russell Ballard Weaver to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Dec 22; ALS, 1 p.
  - Stuart Palmer to James Branch Cabell, [1925] Jan 6; ALS, 3 p.
  - Thomas Hornsly Ferril to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Jan 11; TLS, 1 p.
  - Dorothea Lawrance Mann to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Jan 2; ALS, 3 p.
  - Natalie P. Harris to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Jan 21; ALS, 4 p.
  - Truett Bryan Marshall to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Jan 5; ALS, 1 p.
  - H. B. Fuller to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Jan 11; ALS, 2 p.
  - Fannie Hurst to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Mar 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - "Under the Reading Lamp" by [ George Harrison Phelps], 1925 Jan 20; TMs, 2 p.
  - Lewis Chase to James Branch Cabell, [1925]; ALS, 2 p.
  - Myra Marini to James Branch Cabell, [1925]; ALS, 2 p.
  - Norman A. Hoefeld to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Mar 20; ALS, 2 p.
  - Sydney B. Flower to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Mar 4; TLS, 1 p.
  - Wendell Phillips Bieser to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Mar 5; TLS, 1 p.
  - J. E. Adams to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Mar 2; TLS, 1 p.
  - Samuel Heiman to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Mar 20; ALS, 2 p.
  - Mary Louise Israel to James Branch Cabell, [1925]; ALS, 3 p.
  - Katharine Hayes Amend to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Apr 15; TLS, 2 p.
  - Seth Wakeman to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Apr 6; TLS, 1 p.
  - David Werner Amram to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Apr 5; TLS, 2 p.
  - Edna M. Levey to James Branch Cabell, [1925] Apr 2; ALS, 3 p.
  - Edward A. Niles to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Apr 20; TLS, 4 p.
  - Miss F. M. Roberts to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Apr 8; ALS, 3 p.
  Scrapbook 8
- Scrapbook 8, 1925-1926
  The Silver Stallion
  , with some letters as follows, 84 p.
  - Louis L. Kramer to James Branch Cabell, 1925 May 6; ALS, 1 p.
  - H. de [Key] [Kelton] to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Jun 1; TLS, 1 p.
  - Margaret Root Brown to James Branch Cabell, [1925]; TLS, 2 p.
  - Stanley Olmsted to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Apr 30; TLS, 1 p.
  - [ Egmont Ruschke] to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Jun 29; TLS, 1 p.
  - Martha E. Edler to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Jul 8; TLS, 1 p.
  - Dorothy E. Mock to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Sep 6; ALS, 6 p.
  - W[alter] R[ussell] Bowie to James Branch Cabell, 1925 May 29; ALS, 2 p.
  - Louis Dickstein to James Branch Cabell, 1925 May 18; ALS, 1 p.
  - Edison Skehan to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Feb 11; ALS, 4 p.
  - Natalie P. Harris to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Jan 29; ALS, 4 p.
  - H. Suzanne Eddy to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Feb 5; ALS, 2 p.
  - Harry F. Preller to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Aug 22; ALS, 1 p.
  - W. W. Lange to James Branch Cabell, encl. TL (carbon), 3 pp. list of Cabell first editions, 1924 Dec 29; TLS, 2 p.
  - Geoffrey Landsman to James Branch Cabell, [1925]; ALS, 6 p.
  - F. G. Street, Jr. to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Aug 23; TLS, 2 p.
  - F. G. Street, Jr. to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Sep 10; TLS, 2 p.
  - Mary F. Wickman Porcher to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Nov 30; ALS, 3 p.
  - Marshall McNeil to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Sep 22; TLS, 2 p.
  - Eveline Whalley to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Feb 12; ALS, 1 p.
  - Mary Plum to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Sep 10; ALS, 1 p.
  - Edmond R. Amateis to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Dec 18; ALS, 1 p.
  - Benjamin De Casseres to James Branch Cabell, encl. 1 p. of a TMs speech by De Casseres, 1925 Sep 13; ALS, 1 p.
  - William Arthur Deacon to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Sep 15; TLS, 1 p.
  - Bridget Muller to James Branch Cabell, [1925]; ALS, 2 p.
  - Solomon Malkin to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Aug 13; ALS, 3 p.
  - Emanuel Edward Raices to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Oct 2; ALS, 2 p.
  - Alfred W. Lublin to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Oct 10; ALS, 1 p.
  - I. Adrian Shulimson to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Oct 3; TLS, 5 p.
  - Henry W. Lanier to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Oct 5; TLS, 1 p.
  - F. G. Street, Jr. to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Oct 19; TLS, 1 p.
  - Dorothy Scarborough to James Branch Cabell, encl. 2 pp. TMs list of books for a course in the novel, 1925 Oct 5; TLS, 1 p.
  - A. Grove Day to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Mar 8; TLS, 2 p.
  - Lester Hargrett to James Branch Cabell, [1926] Feb 13; TLS, 1 p.
  - Felix Hargrett to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Feb 22; TLS, 2 p.
  - E. C. Detwiler to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Nov 10; TLS, 1 p.
  - Maurice K. Weil to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Mar 1; TLS, 1 p.
  - Jean O'Brien to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Feb 23; TLS, 1 p.
  - Laura Norton Brown to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Mar 12; TLS, 1 p.
  - Richard Rohman to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Jan 28; ALS, 3 p.
  - Helen Lincoln to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Nov 10; ALS, 3 p.
  - A. Burton Clarke to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Nov 6; TLS, 2 p.
  - I. R. Brussel to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Jan 4; ALS, 1 p.
  - Unknown to James Branch Cabell, [1926]; TL, 1 p.
  - Jessie M. Lyons to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Nov 14; TLS, 1 p.
  - Jane Garrott to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Nov 9; TLS, 1 p.
  - Virginia B. Kingsbury to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Dec 15; TLS, 1 p.
  - Jack Woodford to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Dec 27; TLS, 2 p.
  - Grover Jacoby to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Dec 5; ALS, 1 p.
  - Edward A. Lobb to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Dec 27; ALS, 2 p.
  - Nathaniel Howard to James Branch Cabell, [1926]; ALS, 1 p.
  - Philip C. Duschnes to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Oct 13; ALS, 6 p.
  - Howard Stanley Aronson to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Jan 5; TLS, 1 p.
  - Rose L. Shefska to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Dec 7; ALS, 2 p.
  - Helen Godey Wilson to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Dec 8; ALS, 4 p.
  - Franklin Wentworth to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Mar 10; ALS, 4 p.
  - Karen Rosenblum to James Branch Cabell, [1926] Mar 2; ALS, 2 p.
  - C. Peyton Wertenbaker to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Dec 27; ALS, 4 p.
  - C. W. Beale to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Nov 17; TLS, 1 p.
  - Herbert L. Ganter to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Feb 26; TLS, 1 p.
  - Alfred W. Lublin to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Nov 27; ALS, 1 p.
  - Hal Garrott to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Mar 3; TLS, 1 p.
  - Thomas Bell to James Branch Cabell, [1926] Mar 25; TLS, 2 p.
  - Harry M. East to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Mar 26; TLS, 1 p.
  - Maurice K. Weil to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Mar 22; TLS, 1 p.
  - [William] Leete Stone to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Mar 28; ALS, 3 p.
  - J. [McCutchan] to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Dec 7; ALS, 4 p.
  Scrapbook 9
- Scrapbook 9, 1925-1926
  , w/corrected title page proof for this book, and letters as follows, 82 p.
  - Robert M. McBride & Co. to Knickerbocker Bindery, 1920 Dec 9; TL, 1 p.
  - Georg Muller to Robert M. McBride & Co., 1925 Jan 4; TL, 1 p.
  - Carl Van Doren to James Branch Cabell, 1925 Oct 3; ALS, 1 p.
  - Fred Ashenhurst to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Apr 30; ALS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Apr 22; TLS, 2 p.
  - Carl Van Vechten to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Apr 28; TLS, 1 p.
  - Frances Newman to James Branch Cabell, [1926] Apr 27; TLS, 1 p.
  - Hamilton Owens to James Branch Cabell, w/auto. postscript, 1926 May 11; TLS, 1 p.
  - George Jean Nathan to James Branch Cabell, 1926 May 5; ALS, 1 p.
  - Louis Untermeyer to James Branch Cabell, 1926 May 6; TLS, 1 p.
  - Joseph Wood Krutch to James Branch Cabell, 1926 May 13; TLS, 1 p.
  - Isabel Paterson to James Branch Cabell, 1926 May 12; TLS, 1 p.
  - Benjamin De Casseres to James Branch Cabell, [1926] May 8; ALS, 1 p.
  - Edwin Björkman to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Apr 5; TLS, 1 p.
  - Frank Daniel to James Branch Cabell, 1926 May 4; TLS, 1 p.
  - Sara May MacDonell to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Apr 29; TLS, 3 p.
  - Thomas Geale Rice to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Apr 6; TLS, 2 p.
  - Lloyd E. Smith to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Mar 29; TLS, 1 p.
  - Gertrude N. Lanford to James Branch Cabell, 1926 May 3; ALS, 4 p.
  - Lewis Frambes, Jr. to James Branch Cabell, 1926 May 18; ALS, 1 p.
  - Thomas Watt Tyler to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Apr 30; TLS, 9 p.
  - Hal Garrott to James Branch Cabell, 1926 May 18; TLS, 2 p.
  - H. Baxter Liebler to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Apr 6; TLS, 1 p.
  - Paul F. Husserl to James Branch Cabell, 1926 May 21; TLS, 2 p.
  - Robert M. McBride and Co. to "The Trade", 1926 Jun 1; TL, 1 p.
  - Samuel T. Clover to James Branch Cabell, 1926 May 22; TLS, 1 p.
  - W. P. Dabney to James Branch Cabell, 1926 May 17; TLS, 2 p.
  - Joseph Hergesheimer to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Jun 2; TLS, 3 p.
  - Lawrence W. Fox, Jr. to James Branch Cabell, 1926 May 28; ALS, 2 p.
  - Robert W. Marke to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Jul 1; TLS, 1 p.
  - Norman H. Chase to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Jul 23; TLS, 1 p.
  - Emily N[ewell] Blair to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Jul 31; TLS, 2 p.
  - Greenberg Publisher to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Jun 7; Telegram
  - Lewis S. Baer to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Jun 10; TLS, 1 p.
  - Frances Newman to James Branch Cabell, [1926] Jun 21; TLS, 2 p.
  - Sinclair Lewis to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Jun 26; TLS, 1 p.
  - John Macy to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Aug 15; TLS, 2 p.
  - George Macy to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Jun 18; TLS, 1 p.
  - Howard Blatteis to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Aug 21; TLS, 2 p.
  - Willard D. Firestone to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Aug 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - Harry Lucas to James Branch Cabell, [1926]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Mary K. Stewart to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Aug 9; TLS, 1 p.
  - Beatrice Beeforth to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Sep 8; ALS, 3 p.
  - J. L. F. to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Aug 26; ALS, 2 p.
  - M. Kershaw Walsh to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Aug 4; TLS, 1 p.
  - Donald Maxwell Johnston to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Aug 18; TLS, 1 p.
  - Donald Maxwell Johnston to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Aug 31; TLS, 1 p.
  - Donald Maxwell Johnston to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Sep 3; TLS, 1 p.
  - Henry Alexander to James Branch Cabell, [1926] Aug [7]; ALS, 1 p.
  Scrapbook 10
- Scrapbook 10, 1926-1928
  , with the following letter 106 p.
  - Miles W. Lewis to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Dec 13; TLS, 1 p.